http://www.acsm.org/privacy-policy

Home/ Privacy Policy
In This Section:
PRIVACY POLICY
AMERICAN COLLEGE OF SPORTS MEDICINE, INC. (ACSM) recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of information provided by users of our web site, certified individuals, event registrants, recipients of our e-mail newsletters and all of our members. We created this policy with a fundamental respect for our users’ right to privacy and to guide our relationships with our users. This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for all products and services of ACSM. A current list of our membership categories, certification levels, and events can be found at http://www.acsm.org.
Information Collection and Use
ACSM collects information from our web site users, members and non-members. In this section of our privacy policy, we will describe the type of information we collect and how we use it to provide better services to our members.
Membership and Event Registration
When applying for membership or event registration through our web site, users are required to give their contact information (such as name, mailing address, e-mail address and phone number). We also may collect demographic information (such as title, company information and areas of interest, etc…). For internal purposes, we use this information to communicate with members and provide requested services, and, for our web site visitors, to provide a more personalized experience on our sites. We use aggregate demographic information about our audience to improve our service, for marketing purposes and/or industry reporting purposes.
For our services that require payment (such as membership dues, events, products and journals), we also collect credit card information (such as card holder name, credit card number, billing address, credit card security code and expiration date), which is used for billing purposes only, and is not otherwise shared.
Surveys
From time to time we invite users to provide information via surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether to disclose requested contact information (such as name and mailing address) and demographic information (such as zip code or job title). In addition to other uses set forth in this policy, contact information collected in connection with surveys is used to monitor or improve the use and satisfaction of the site.
Interactive Features
At our site, we offer interactive and community features such as discussion forums found in the communities section of the “Members Only” page. Note that all personal information sent or posted via such features becomes public information for which we are not responsible. Discussion forums are regulated by the “Terms and Use” located on the communities page.
Tell-A-Friend
If users elect to use our referral service for informing a friend about our sites and services, we may ask them for the friend's name, job title and e-mail address. ACSM will store and use this information to send the friend an invitation. This information may also be used to provide information about our company and related products and services. The friend may contact us as specified in the tell-a-friend message to request that no further communications be sent.
Communications with Us
We have features where users can submit information to us (such as our feedback forms or committee interest forms). Letters to the editor and similar submissions may be made public. Requests for service, support or information may be forwarded as needed to best respond to a specific request. We may retain e-mails and other information sent to us for our internal administrative purposes, and to help us to serve customers better.
Communications from Us: Service Updates, Special Offers
In order to best serve our members, we may send updates that contain important information about our sites and services. For example, we send new members a welcoming message, and verify password and username for our password-protected sites. We may also communicate with a user to provide requested services and for account-related issues via e-mail, phone or regular mail.
We offer our users the option to receive information about our organization, related products, services and special events. Users can choose not to receive these communications, as set forth in our Permission section below.
Automatic Data Collection
Our web sites have features that automatically collect information from users, to deliver content specific to users' interests and to honor their preferences. This information assists us in creating sites that will serve the needs of our users.
We use "cookies," a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Cookies benefit the user by requiring login only once, thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the cookies, they may be limited in the use of some areas of our site. Additionally, we may note some of the pages the user visits on our site through the use of pixel tags (also called clear gifs). The use of cookies and pixels enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our sites.
Some of our publishers or sponsors use cookies on our sites in announcements. However, we have no access to or control over these publishers or sponsors cookies; we urge users to read their privacy policies for information.
For our internal purposes, we gather date, time, browser type, navigation history and IP address of all visitors to our site. This information does not contain information that can identify users personally. We use this information for our internal security audit log, trend analysis and system administration, and to gather broad demographic information about our user base for aggregate use.
We may combine demographic information supplied by a member at the time of application with site usage data to provide general profiles, in aggregate non-personally identifiable form, about our users and their preferences in the content of the site. We may share this composite information with our sponsors or publishers to help them better understand our services
Sharing Your Information
When we offer co-branded, customized or sponsored products and services, or when we join with other parties to provide specific products or services, we may share (provide and receive) personal information with them. Unless prohibited by law, we do not share credit card information with such third parties.
These sponsors will use the information according to their own privacy policies, and we urge participants to read those policies before registering.
On occasion, we may rent lists of targeted names and offline and online contact information for marketing purposes to reputable third parties, whose products or services we think you might find of interest. We give users the option of not having their name or contact information disclosed to third parties, as set forth in the Permission section below.
We may share aggregate information, which is not personally identifiable, with others. This information may include usage and demographic data, but it will not include personal information.
Correction/Updating Information
Members may update their personally identifiable information (such as a change in address, email, or phone number), by logging into the members only portion of our web site. Should a non-member need to change their personally identifiable information, they can contact Member Services at 317-637-9200, or e-mail membership@acsm.org. If a user no longer desires our product(s)/service(s), the user should contact Member Services for the applicable product or service or email membership@acsm.org.
Permission
Our users are given the opportunity to choose whether to receive information from our sponsors or publishers and us not directly related to the registered services. Users also have the opportunity to choose whether to have personal information shared with third parties for marketing purposes. Instructions for how to exercise this choice are contained in e-mails sent by us, on our product web sites and in each of our publications. Should you wish to not have your information shared with ACSM approved third parties, please email ACSM at membership@acsm.org .  Please note that we will endeavor to implement requests within a reasonable time, although for a time users may continue to receive mailings, etc., transmitted based on information released prior to the implementation of the request. Users will continue to receive information directly related to their registered services, so they always are kept informed.
Security
We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving your information. Additionally, we implement commercially reasonable security measures at our physical facilities to protect against loss or misuse of your information.
Links
Our web sites contain links to other sites. ACSM is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each web site to which we may link that may collect personally identifiable information. As well, we are not responsible for the misuse of ACSM’s name, products or services listed on other sites.
Notification and Changes
If we change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so our users are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under which circumstances, if any, we disclose it. Users should check this policy frequently to keep abreast of any changes.
For questions about this privacy statement, or questions concerning the practices of this site or any dealings with American College of Sports Medicine, Inc. contact:
Corporate Communications
American College of Sports Medicine, Inc.
Planned Giving (Discovery Society)
Paffenbarger-Blair Fund for Epidemiological Research on Physical Activity
Which Certification is right for you?
